Guide to the Burundi Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Burundi collection
1964-2009
MS 1506
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.77
(5 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political and social conditions in Burundi and a photograph of a Mubira woman with a lip disc.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the first accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to the political and social conditions in Burundi and a photograph of a Mubira woman with a lip disc.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Burundi -- Description and travel; Burundi -- Politics and government; Burundi -- Social conditions
- Original Accession, 1964-1991
  - Political organizations: newsletters; journals; printed material, 1964, 1970, 1975, 1983, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Essays and reviews, 1968, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "L'Appel de Kiriri": Lors de la Visite du Président du Comité Militaire pour le Salut National et Président de la République, 1988 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Periodicals, 1988, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General information pamphlets; brochures; booklets, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, 1996; Accession 1999-M-004
  - "Comment Vivre en Democratie au Burundi?", 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Additional Material, 1977-1996; Accession 2000-M-012
  - Amnesty International USA, "Burundi: Interview with Mission Delegate just returned from Scene of Coup", 1993 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bagaza, Jean-Baptiste, "Discours", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Deuxième Conférence de Presse du Président Melchior Ndadaye", 1993 September (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ifaranga?, 1984 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Ndikuryayo, Jean Bosco, "Les Temps Qui Jugent", 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Statut: Fonds de Solidaritédes Travailleurs de l'Enseignement", 1990 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - UNICEF
    - For a Better Future, Assistance aux Enfants Non Accompagnés (AENA), 1995 August (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Declaration of Commitment to the Protection of the Children of Burundi, 1996 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional Material, 1979; Accession 2010-M-097; (1 box)
  - Printed materials
    - Le Guide: organe d'information de l'Union des Travailleurs du Burundi, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ubumwe, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of a Mubira woman with a disc in her pierced lips, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 1974-2009; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 1974-2009 (Box 1, Folder 1)